Register of the Ray Lyman Wilbur papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- HERBERT HOOVER FILE, 1916-1964 (Boxes 19-21)
  - Correspondence
    - Hoover, Herbert, 1912-1948
      - 1942-1948 (Box-folder 21: 6)
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1945 October 24
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1945 December 27
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur (plus note from "Mike" to Wilbur), 1947 April 3
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1947 May 5
        - Gridiron Dinner address by Herbert Hoover, pamphlet, 8-vo, Washington, with signed dedication by Herbert Hoover, 1947 May 10
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 4-to, Rio de Janeiro, from Herbert Hoover, Jr., to R. L. Wilbur, 1947 July 4
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1947 October 2
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1947 October 15
        - Typed carbon Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to Palmer (Parmer) Fuller, 1947 October 20
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1947 October 30
        - Telegram, 1 p., oblong 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with carbon reply, 1947 November 7
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, plus Wilbur to Hoover, 1947 November 15, 18
        - Telegram, 1 p., oblong 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with typed carbon reply and manuscript notation, 1947 December 4
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, together with two ALs from friends of R. L. Wilbur to R. L. Wilbur, 1947 December 4
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1948 February 28
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1948 March 8
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1948 March 19
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with typed carbon reply, 1948 March 19
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1948 March 19
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from secretary of Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with telegram, 1948 May 27
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1948 June 11
        - Tearsheet article from Reader's Digest, 1 leaf, with pencil manuscript notation from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur
        - Four miscellaneous pieces by and to Hugh Gibson with carbon and typed attachment, 4 pp. (8 pp. altogether)
        - 15 miscellaneous pieces (20 pieces) of correspondence, typed carbon replies, etc.
          Includes five typed N and L by Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, various dates.
        - Eight miscellaneous telegrams and typed carbon telegrams, oblong 8-vo, V. P., V. D. from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur (7 from Hoover to Wilbur, 1 from Wilbur to Hoover)
        - "Itemized list of items found in safe"
    - Re: health of Hoover children, 1941-1946 (Box-folder 21: 7)
  - Miscellany, 1928-1964 (Box-folder 21: 8)
    Clippings, progress report, poem, invitations. Includes ten miscellaneous pieces related to Herbert Hoover; typed carbon letters, Stanford Alumni Almanac (Autumn 1964), etc., typed carbon manuscript, "Accomplishments of the Administration in the First Sixteen Months," and Stanford Alumni Almanac (Autumn 1964).
  - Printed material, 1931-1943 (Box-folder 21: 9)
    Pamphlets relating to Herbert Hoover.
  - Reports, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 21: 10)
    President's Economic Mission to Germany and Austria. Original folder label: "H.H. - Material on Food Mission /47". Front of folder had written in pencil "Bibliography for New Deal."
  - Speeches by Herbert Hoover, 1925-1953 (Box-folder 21: 11)
- INSTITUTE OF PACIFIC RELATIONS FILE, 1920-1960 (Boxes 22-50)
  Minutes, reports, correspondence, speech and hearing transcripts, conference proceedings, memoranda, bibliographies, pamphlets, clippings, and printed articles relating to the Institute and to the Pacific Basin and Asia, arranged by form.
  - Administrative materials (Box 22)
    - General. Chronological files, 1925-1960
      - Honolulu Conference, 1925-1926
      - Honolulu Conference, 1925-1926 (Box 23)
      - Honolulu Conference, 1925-1926 (Box 24)
      - 1926 June-December
      - 1926 December - 1927 April (Box 25)
      - 1927 May-December (Box 26)
      - 1928 January-September (Box 27)
      - 1928 October - 1929 June (Box 28)
      - 1929 July - 1935 December (Box 29)
      - 1936 January - 1937 June (Box 30)
      - 1937 July - 1938 December (Box 31)
      - 1939 January - 1940 March (Box 32)
      - 1940 April - 1941 December (Box 33)
      - 1942 January - 1943 December (Box 34)
      - 1944 January - 1945 January (Box 35)
      - 1945 April - 1946 June (Box 36)
      - 1946 July - 1948 June (Box 37)
      - 1948 July - 1952, 1960 (Box 38)
    - Administrative Assistant's office file, 1947-1953
    - Committees
      - American Council
        - List of committees of the American Group, 1926 October (Box-folder 39: 1)
        - Papers prepared for the Honolulu Conference, 1927 (Box-folder 39: 2)
        - Extracts from replies to the American Group questionnaire, 1927 October 21 (Box-folder 39: 3)
        - Miscellaneous issuances of the American Group, 1927 (Box-folder 39: 4)
        - Minutes of meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1929 April 5 (Box-folder 39: 5)
        - Minutes of meetings, 1928-1931 (Box-folder 39: 6)
      - National Council. Report of research activities, 1928 May-September (Box-folder 39: 7)
      - American Research Committee. Outlines of research projects, 1926 (Box-folder 39: 8)
      - China Committee. Letter to Mr. Loomis describing work of the committee, 1925 December 17 (Box-folder 39: 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1926-1952 (Box-folder 39: 10-13)
      Letters, reports, lists, minutes, form letters and memoranda, correspondence and other materials relating to a trip to the Far East by Dr. and Mrs. Wilbur in 1926; also includes a printed transcript of Senate hearings and a list of delegates to the Tokyo Peace Conference.
    - Miscellaneous. Minutes, 1936 (Box-folder 40: 1)
    - Clippings [See: OVERSIZE FILE], 1924-1929
  - Correspondence, 1927-1949
    - General. Persons and groups interested in the Institute of Pacific Relations, 1927-1949 (Box-folder 40: 2)
    - Carter, Edward C., 1923-1947 (Box-folder 40: 3)
    - Condliffe, J. B. Letter to Mr. Loomis telling of work done in Australia, 1925 November 11 (Box-folder 40: 4)
    - Davis, J. Merle (partial itemized list) (Box-folder 40: 5-7)
      - Letter with enclosure, entitled "Inside Story of the (Honolulu) Conference,", 1925 September 30
      - Letter to Ray L. Wilbur with enclosure, entitled "Suggestions Regarding the Baltimore Conference,", 1925 December 9
      - Letter to Ray L. Wilbur with enclosures of letters by C. F. Loomis, 1929 February 20
      - Letter to Ray L. Wilbur with an enclosed interview with Henry L. Stimson, 1929 March 21
      - Letter to Ray L. Wilbur summarizing impressions of the Kyoto Conference, 1930 January 7
    - Hall, H. Duncan (Box-folder 40: 8)
      - Letter from J. B. Condliffe to C. F. Loomis, 1926 February 18
      - Letter from H. Duncan Hall to C. F. Loomis, with enclosed report of meeting of the British Institute of International Affairs (1926 April 7), 1926 April 6
      - Letter from H. Duncan Hall to Ray L. Wilbur with enclosed note of the Pacific Conference, 1926 June 8
      - Report of the first meeting of the Institute of Pacific Relations, 1925
    - Lattimore, Owen, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 40: 9)
    - State Department, 1917-1945 (Box-folder 40: 10)
  - Conferences
    - Honolulu Conference, 1925
      - Executive documents (Box-folder 40: 11)
      - Epitome of findings of meeting held by Australian members (Box-folder 40: 12)
      - Minutes of meeting of the Committee on Permanent Organization, 1925 July 8 (Box-folder 40: 13)
      - Miscellaneous documents and papers (Box-folder 40: 14)
      - Letters from delegates to the conference, giving their impressions, criticisms, and suggestions (Box-folder 40: 15)
      - List of members (Box-folder 40: 16)
      - Minutes of meeting of the Organization Committee, 1925 July 15 (Box-folder 40: 17)
      - Minutes of meeting of the Program Committee, 1925 July 15 (Box-folder 40: 18)
      - Who's who in IPR (Box-folder 40: 19)
    - Honolulu Conference, 1927
      - Cable from Ray L. Wilbur to President Coolidge (Box-folder 41: 1)
      - Documents and papers (Box-folder 41: 2-4)
      - Miscellaneous issuances (Box-folder 41: 5)
      - Press releases (Box-folder 41: 6)
      - Program and outline of second session, 1927 July 15-29 (Box-folder 41: 7)
    - Kyoto Conference, 1929
      - Opening statement by Jerome D. Greene, 1929 October 28 (Box-folder 41: 8)
      - Opening address of Australian delegation (Box-folder 41: 9)
      - Report on discussions of the Round Table on International Relations in the Pacific (Box-folder 41: 10)
      - Memorandum on the international settlement at Shanghai (Box-folder 41: 11)
      - Opening statement of the British Group (Box-folder 42: 1)
      - Choice of topics for the programme (Box-folder 42: 2)
      - Opening address of New Zealand delegation (Box-folder 42: 3)
      - Report of the Philippine situation by the Philippine delegation (Box-folder 42: 4)
    - Hangchow Conference, 1931
      - "The Standard of Living in China and Japan," by C. Delisle Burns (Box-folder 42: 5)
      - Draft syllabus for the study of diplomatic machinery in the Pacific (Box-folder 42: 6)
      - "The Report of Mr. Justice Feetham and the Future of Shanghai," by C. L. Hsia (Box-folder 42: 7)
      - Preliminary census statistics of Oriental residents in continental U.S., 1930 (Box-folder 42: 8)
      - "Foreign Investments in China," by C. F. Remer (Box-folder 42: 9)
    - Banff (Canada) Conference, reports and documents, 1933 (Box-folder 42: 10)
    - Virginia Beach Conference, 1939
      - Secretariat documents, nos. 1-13, 15-21, 23 (Box-folder 42: 11)
      - Pacific Council documents, nos. 1, 5-14 (Box-folder 42: 12)
      - Pacific Council minutes, no. 1 (Box-folder 42: 13)
      - International Research Committee minutes, nos. 1-3 (Box-folder 42: 14)
      - International Research Committee documents, nos. 1-5 (Box-folder 42: 15)
    - Lucknow Conference, clipping from the Manchester Guardian, 1950 October 19 (Box-folder 42: 16)
  - Educational materials
    - General. School programs and bibliographies (Box-folder 42: 17)
    - "A Course in Pacific Relations for Secondary Schools,", 1932 September (Box-folder 42: 18-19)
  - Publications, circa 1942-1945 (Box-folder 42: 20)
    Pamphlets. Includes list of officers and the executive committee of the Institute of Pacific Relations, San Francisco Bay Region and IPR: Aims, Organization, Activities.
  - Reports and statements
    - Condliffe, J. B., "An Experiment in Diagnosis,", undated (Box-folder 42: 21)
    - Suenobu, Mr., interview, undated (Box-folder 42: 22)
    - Urice, Jay A., report on IPR, 1925 (Box-folder 42: 23)
    - Zumoto, M., address before the YMCA luncheon, Nuuanu, circa 1925 (Box-folder 42: 24)
    - Shidehara, Baron (Minister of Foreign Affairs), interview, 1926 April 15 (Box-folder 42: 25)
    - Faris, Ellsworth, "The Superiority of Race,", 1927 (Box-folder 42: 26)
    - Latourett, Kenneth S., "Status of the Far East on Curricula of Schools and Colleges in the U.S.,", 1927 (Box-folder 43: 1)
    - Warnshuis, A. L., "Relationships of Protestant Mission Boards in America to Churches in Japan, Korea, China, and the Philippines,", 1927 (Box-folder 43: 2)
    - Wilson, Lester M., "Summary of Legislation Concerning Public Control of Private Schools and Teaching of Religion in Public Schools in U.S.,", 1927 (Box-folder 43: 3)
    - Gamio, Manuel
      - "Commentaries on the Indo-Iberic Countries of the Pacific,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 4)
      - "Number, Origin, and Geographic Distribution of Mexican Immigrants in the U.S.,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 5)
    - Yashnov, E. E., "Chinese Agriculture in Northern Manchuria,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 6)
    - Lam, Fred K., "Survey of the Chinese People in Hawaii,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 7)
    - Burpee, Lawrence J., "A North American Forum,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 8)
    - Coats, R. H., "Import and Export of Capital from Canada,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 9)
    - Currelly, C. T., "Statement Regarding Opportunities for Study of Chinese Art in Toronto,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 10)
    - Laufer, Barthold, "The Gest Chinese Research Library of McGill,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 11)
    - Wallace, Edward W., "Christian Missions in China,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 12)
    - Yui, David Z. T., "China and Pacific Relations During 1927-1929," (Box-folder 43: 13)
    - Asari, J., "Outline of Conditions of Employment of Women and Young Persons in Factories and Mines in Japan,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 14)
    - Funatsu, Tatsuichiro, "Nationalist Attitudes Toward Foreign Industrial Establishments in China,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 15)
    - Komura, Shunzaburo, "The New Pacific and Mediterranean Treaties as a Means of Furthering Peace,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 16)
    - Nagae, Hampei, "Machine Age and Religion, a Japanese Layman's View,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 17)
    - Nitobe, Inazo, "Statement on Japan's Preparedness for International Cooperation,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 18)
    - Odagiri, Masnoske, "Japanese Investment in China,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 19)
    - Shibusawa, Viscount, "Peace on the Pacific, Japan and U.S.,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 20)
    - Tomoeda, T., "A Short Remark on Shinto,", 1929 (Box-folder 43: 21)
    - Norman, Herbert E., "The Establishment of a Modern State in Japan,", 1939 (Box-folder 43: 22)
    - "Notes on Conditions in the Occupied Areas of East Central China,", 1939 (Box-folder 43: 23)
    - "Soviet Relations in the Far East, 1931-1939," (Box-folder 43: 24)
    - Carlson, Major Evans F., "The Chinese Army, Its Organization and Military Efficiency,", 1939 (Box-folder 43: 25)
    - Farley, Miriam S., "Problem of Japanese Trade Expansion in the Post-War Situation,", 1939 (Box-folder 43: 26)
    - "Effects of Sino-Japanese Conflict on American Educational and Philanthropic Enterprises in China,", 1939 (Box-folder 44: 1)
    - Avarna, Carlo and Maria Luisa Boggeri, "Italy and the Far East,", 1939 (Box-folder 44: 2)
    - Pe, M. Thein, "What Happened in Burma,", 1944 (Box-folder 44: 3)
  - Subject file, 1920-1949
    - Alert. Letters and newsletters relating to charges of communism in the Institute of Pacific Relations, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 44: 4)
    - Amerasia. Serial issues and clippings, 1941-1947 (Box-folder 44: 5)
    - Asia. Mimeographed reports, 1957 (Box-folder 44: 6)
    - California Colleges in China. Letters and miscellany, 1929-46 (Box-folder 44: 7-8)
    - China Institute in America. Primarily letters, 1930-1948 (Box-folder 44: 9)
    - China
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 44: 10)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 45: 1)
      - Nankai University (Box-folder 45: 2)
      - Shanghai American School and Shanghai College (Box-folder 45: 3)
      - Various universities and colleges (Box-folder 45: 4)
      - Various welfare associations and organizations (Box-folder 45: 5)
    - Chinese, various individuals (Box-folder 45: 6)
    - Chinese National Association of the Mass Education Movement (Box-folder 45: 7)
    - China and the Rockefeller Foundation (Box-folder 45: 8)
    - China Medical Board (Rockefeller Foundation), 1924 (Box-folder 45: 9)
    - China Medical Board, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 46: 1-4)
    - China. Peking Union Medical College, 1922-27 (Box-folder 46: 5-8)
    - Japan
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 46: 9)
      - American School in (Box-folder 46: 10)
    - Japanese
      - Immigration and colonization problems (Box-folder 46: 11)
      - Miscellaneous organizations, publications (Box-folder 47: 1)
      - Individuals (Box-folder 47: 2)
      - In the United States. Relocation, internees, evacuees (Box-folder 47: 3-4)
    - K-L (Box-folder 47: 5)
    - Manchuria. Letters, printed article and typescript report, 1931-1946 (Box-folder 47: 6)
    - O (Box-folder 47: 7)
    - Pacific Botanical Foundation (Box-folder 47: 8)
    - Pacific Geographical Society (Box-folder 47: 9)
    - Pacific Fisheries (Box-folder 48: 1)
    - Pacific House (Asia House), 1937-1943 (Box-folder 48: 2-7)
    - Pacific Ocean School of Social Science (Box-folder 48: 9)
    - Pacific Ocean School of Social Science (Box-folder 49: 1-6)
    - Philippines. Memorandum and report, 1924-1925 (Box-folder 49: 7)
    - Riggs Foundation, 1944-1947 (Box-folder 49: 8)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, Board of Trustees (Box-folder 49: 9)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, reports (Box-folder 49: 10-16)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, reports (Box-folder 50: 1-9)
    - University of Hawaii, Oriental Institute Journal (Box-folder 50: 10)
- INTERIOR DEPARTMENT FILE, 1924-1946 (Boxes 51-78)
  Correspondence with other government departments, invitations, memoranda, press releases, scrapbooks, budgets, minutes, reports, speech transcripts, pamphlets, clippings, charts, and printed articles relating to Indian affairs, land and water use and reclamation projects, oil conservation, oil shale leases, and other subjects, arranged by subject.
  - General
    - General. Notes, certificate copy, letter and draft statement, 1930-1933 (Box-folder 51: 1)
    - Correspondence with other government departments. Relates largely to personnel matters
      - Interstate Commerce Commission. Letter and telegram, 1931 January-February (Box-folder 51: 2)
      - Justice Department. Letters and miscellany, 1929 February - 1932 May (Box-folder 51: 3)
      - Labor Department. Letters and miscellany, 1929 March - 1932 December (Box-folder 51: 4-5)
      - Navy Department. Letters and miscellany, 1929 March - 1933 January (Box-folder 51: 6-7)
      - Post Office. Letters and miscellany, 1929 March - 1933 January (Box-folder 51: 8)
      - State Department. Letters and miscellany, 1929 March - 1933 January (Box-folder 52: 1-2)
      - Treasury Department. Letters and miscellany, 1929 May - 1933 March (Box-folder 52: 3)
      - War Department. Letters and miscellany, 1929 March - 1933 January (Box-folder 52: 4-6)
    - Invitations
      - 1929 March 6 - September 25 (Box-folder 53: 1-6)
      - 1929 October 15 - 1930 February 13 (Box-folder 54: 1-6)
      - 1930 March 13 - September 19 (Box-folder 55: 1-6)
      - 1930 November 12 - 1931 March 16 (Box-folder 56: 1-7)
      - 1931 March 17 - September 30 (Box-folder 57: 1-5)
      - 1931 October 1 - 1932 March 28 (Box-folder 58: 1-5)
      - 1932 March 29 - 1933 February 11 (Box-folder 59: 1-5)
    - Memoranda. Primarily memoranda written by Northcutt Ely, Executive Assistant to the Secretary, and others, relating to Indian affairs, oil lands, reclamation and other subjects, 1929 March - 1933 February (Box-folder 60: 1-7)
    - Press releases, 1933 (Box-folder 61: 1)
    - Scrapbooks. Photographs of coal mining camps and living conditions, circa 1923 (Box-folder 61: 2-3)
  - Alaska Reindeer Service. Survey, 1933 February (Box-folder 62: 1)
  - Appropriation Bill for 1933. Printed material, 1932 (Box-folder 62: 2)
  - Archives Building. Letters, 1929-1930 (Box-folder 62: 3)
  - Art Center (Wayside Beautification campaign). Letters and printed material, 1929-1931 (Box-folder 62: 4)
  - Bird Conservation Commission. Minutes, 1932 December (Box-folder 62: 5)
  - Economic Conference. Memoranda and budgets relating to a meeting between the Economy Committee of the U.S. House of Representatives, President Hoover and Hoover Administration officials, 1932 (Box-folder 62: 6)
  - Education
    - Bureau of Education (proposed). Letters, 1929 February - 1933 January (Box-folder 62: 7-9)
    - Education by Radio. Correspondence, minutes and miscellany, 1929 December - 1932 June (Box-folder 63: 1-2)
    - Vocational education. Letters and non-printed material, 1931 January - 1932 October (Box-folder 63: 3)
  - Employment. Survey for Pacific Coast. Typescript report with correspondence, 1929 December - 1930 May (Box-folder 63: 4)
  - Engineering
    - General. Letters, 1929 March - 1932 June (Box-folder 63: 5)
    - Nevada, Biennial Report of the State Engineer, 1931 (Box-folder 63: 6)
  - Federal Farm Board and farm relief. Report, printed speech transcript and correspondence, 1929 February - 1930 October (Box-folder 63: 7)
  - Federal Home Loan Bank Board. Letters and a budget, 1932 August-November (Box-folder 63: 8)
  - Federal Power Commission. Printed material, memoranda, letters and speeches, 1924-1932 (Box-folder 63: 9-10)
  - Federal Power Commission (Box-folder 64: 1-3)
  - Federal Radio Commission. Printed material, budgets, annual report and correspondence, 1929 March - 1932 December (Box-folder 64: 4)
  - Geological Survey. Letters and reports, 1929 March - 1932 August (Box-folder 64: 5)
  - Hawaii. Relates to Massie rape case, 1932-1945 (Box-folder 64: 6-7)
    Folder 6, titled "Massie Case, Mrs. Thomas Hedges (Wife of Lieut.)" includes miscellaneous typed Ls, carbon L, telegrams, newspaper articles and clippings, etc. (51 pieces), all relative to the Massie Case, 1931-32, which involved the then Secretary of the Interior, R. L. Wilbur. Together 109 pieces, various sizes, V. P., V. D. including letters from Governor Judd of Hawaii and other government officials (plus 2d folder with 78 pieces).
  - Howard University. Letters, 1929 March - 1932 June (Box-folder 64: 8)
  - Indians
    - General. Bulletins, reports, letters, pamphlets, and printed articles, 1919-1946 (Box-folder 65: 1-3)
      Includes press release and report to Senator William H. King relating to the Interior Department Appropriations bill for 1934.
    - Indian Office, 1929 February - 1933 January (Box-folder 65: 4-6)
    - Pueblo Lands Board. Correspondence, 1929 March - 1933 January (Box-folder 66: 1-2)
  - Klamath Lake. Report on the restoration of Klamath Lake, 1932 (Box-folder 66: 3)
  - Land
    - General. Printed material, report, letters and charts, 1924-1930 (Box-folder 66: 4)
    - General Land Office. Letters and printed material, 1929 March - 1933 February (Box-folder 66: 5)
    - Public Land Commission. Reports, clippings, letters and correspondence with Herbert Hoover, 1929-1931 (Box-folder 66: 6-7)
  - National Parks. Letters, report, minutes and miscellany, 1929 April - 1931 October (Box-folder 67: 1-2)
  - Oil. Relates primarily to charges by Ralph S. Kelley regarding oil shale leases
    - General. Speech transcripts, 1926-1930 (Box-folder 67: 3)
      - Conservation
        - General. Reports on mineral conservation and compilations of newspaper and magazine editorials, 1929 (Box-folder 67: 4-5)
        - Federal Oil Conservation Board. Letters, speech transcripts, memoranda, telegrams, printed material, charts, pamphlets, reports, press releases, 1929-1933 (Box-folder 67: 6)
        - Federal Oil Conservation Board (Box-folder 68; 1-6)
        - Interstate Oil Conservation Compact. Reports, letters, and printed material, 1929-1932 (Box-folder 69: 1-3)
          Includes a report by Northcutt Ely, "The Interdependence of the States in Oil Conservation."
      - Policy. Comments received relating to oil exploration on public lands. Letters and clippings, 1929-1931 (Box-folder 69: 4)
      - Tariff. Letters, clippings and telegrams, 1929-1931 (Box-folder 69: 5)
    - Chronology of events (Box-folder 69: 6)
    - Clippings
      - General (Box-folder 69: 7)
      - General (Box-folder 70: 1-5)
      - General (Box-folder 71: 1-3)